<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<appendix id="ap_faq">
<title>The Sylpheed-Claws FAQ</title>
    <section>
    <title>What are the differences between Sylpheed-Claws and Sylpheed?</title>
    <para>
	Sylpheed-Claws is the <emphasis>extended</emphasis> version of
	Sylpheed, therefore you will find that it has all the features that
	Sylpheed has and a lot more besides. It also includes some modified
	dialogues to enhance usability. Further information can be found at 
	<ulink url="http://www.sylpheed-claws.net/features.php">
	http://www.sylpheed-claws.net/features.php</ulink>.
    </para></section>
    <section>
    <title>What does the word <quote>Sylpheed</quote> mean?</title>
    <para>
	<quote>Sylpheed</quote> is a corruption of the word 
	<emphasis>Sylph</emphasis>. Sylphs are invisible beings (spirits) of
	the air.
    </para></section>
    <section>
    <title>Does Sylpheed-Claws allow me to write HTML styled messages?</title>
    <para>
	No. A discussion has gone on around this topic, and the outcome was that
	HTML mail is not wanted. If you really need to send HTML, you can of
	course attach a webpage to an email.
    </para></section>
    <section>
    <title>How can I submit patches, report bugs, and talk about Sylpheed-Claws
	with others?</title>
    <para>
	Patches should be submitted via the SourceForge project Patch Tracker at 
	<ulink url='http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=25528&amp;atid=384600'>
	http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=25528&amp;atid=384600</ulink>, 
	but please follow the patch guidelines at 
	<ulink url="http://www.sylpheed-claws.net/devel.php">
	http://www.sylpheed-claws.net/devel.php</ulink>.
    </para>
    <para>
	 Bug reports should be submitted at our Bugzilla, 
	 <ulink url="http://www.thewildbeast.co.uk/sylpheed-claws/bugzilla/">
	http://www.thewildbeast.co.uk/sylpheed-claws/bugzilla/</ulink>.
    </para>
    <para>
	To talk to others, you should join the Sylpheed-Claws users' mailing
	list. Details can be found at 
	<ulink url="http://www.sylpheed-claws.net/MLs.php">
	http://www.sylpheed-claws.net/MLs.php</ulink>.
    </para>
    </section>
    <section>
    <title>Does Sylpheed-Claws have an anti-spam feature?</title>
    <para>
	Yes. It has a SpamAssassin and a Bogofilter plugin. You can find 
	details of it on the
	<link linkend="ch_plugins">Extending Sylpheed-Claws</link> chapter.
    </para>
    <para>
	You can also use other spam filters via the <quote>Filtering</quote> and
	<quote>Actions</quote> features, such as Bogofilter. Instructions on how
	use Bogofilter with Sylpheed-Claws can be found on the
	<ulink url="http://bogofilter.sourceforge.net/faq.shtml#with-sc">
	Bogofilter FAQ</ulink>.
    </para></section>
    <section>
    <title>Does Sylpheed-Claws support Return Receipts?</title>
    <para>
	Yes.
	To request a Return Receipt use <quote>Options/Request Return 
	Receipt</quote> in the Compose window. When you receive a message that
	requests a Return Receipt a notification area is shown just above the
	message view. You can either use the <quote>Send receipt</quote> button,
	or ignore the request - no receipts are sent automatically.
    </para>
    <para>
	If you do not ever want to send Return Receipts then you can use the
	option <quote>Never send Return Receipts</quote> in the
	<quote>Configuration/Preferences/Other</quote> page.
    </para></section>
    <section>
    <title>How can I make Sylpheed-Claws notify me when new mail
    arrives?</title>
    <para>
	Go to <quote>Configuration/Preferences</quote>, in the <quote>Mail
	Handling/Receiving</quote> section, use the settings for <quote>Run
	command</quote> in the <quote>After receiving new mail</quote>
	frame. Alternatively, use the Trayicon plugin.
    </para></section>
    <section>
    <title>Why are special characters (e.g. umlauts) not displayed
    correctly?</title>
    <para>
	In most cases, this is caused by emails with broken encodings. You can
	try to force it using the <quote>View/Character Encoding</quote>
	submenu.
    </para></section>
    <section>
    <title>Can I quote just a section of the original message when
    replying?</title>
    <para>
	Yes, select the section of the message that you want to quote and use
	<quote>Reply</quote>.
    </para></section>
    <section>
    <title>Where can I find the answers to more FAQs about
    Sylpheed-Claws?</title>
    <para>
	An enlarged, user-contributed FAQ can be found on the Sylpheed-Claws
	website, <ulink url="http://www.sylpheed-claws.net/faq/">
	http://www.sylpheed-claws.net/faq/</ulink>
    </para>
    </section>
</appendix>
